turtlerockstudios.com 2016-06-02

# Privacy Policy | Turtle Rock Studios

_Effective November 5, 2015_

**_Our Privacy Commitment_**

Turtle Rock Studios, Inc. (“ ** _TRS,_** ” “ ** _we,_** ” “ ** _us_** ” or “ ** _our_** ”) is committed to respecting the privacy rights and concerns of all users of the turtlerockstudios.com website (the “ ** _Site_** ”) (we refer to the Site, the services made available through the Site, collectively, as the “ ** _TRS Services_** ”).  As such, we have established and implemented this Privacy Policy to inform visitors to the Site and users of TRS Services of how we use and protect the information we collect through the Site.  By visiting or browsing the Site(s) or using the TRS Services, you consent to TRS’s collection, use, storage, deletion, transfer to the United States, and disclosure of personal information relating to you as set forth in this Privacy Policy.  This Privacy Policy is effective as of the date set forth above and is only applicable to the Site(s) and not to any other website that you may be able to access from the Site(s) which may have its own data collection and use practices and policies.

This policy answers the following questions:

–   What information do we collect about you and how do we use it?

–   Will we share your personal information with third parties?

–   What choices do you have about the collection and use of your personal information?

–   What security measures do we take to safeguard your personal information?

**_WHAT  INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU AND HOW DO WE USE IT?_**

_Types of Information We Collect_

Personal information means information that can be used to identify and contact you.  The Site and TRS Services may collect personal information from you including your email address, name and cookies.   If you do not want to disclose certain personal information to us, you will not be able to access certain aspects of the TRS Services, such as forums.

Personal information is collected from you when you create an account on the Site; subscribe to our newsletter; participate in Site feedback, questionnaires, surveys, contests, sweepstakes, or other promotions or receive customer or technical support.

To create an account to use the TRS Services, we will require you to provide certain information to create your account, including your email address, user name and password.

If you sign up to the TRS Services through Facebook, Twitter or Google Plus, we may also collect personally identifiable information from these social networking sites and database services, including the Facebook Groups that you belong to.

_How We Use Your Personal Information_

_Newsletters_.  TRS may use your email address or other personal information to send you commercial or marketing messages including, without limitation, newsletters, promotions, updates, special offers, and email communications about our products or services.  We will also use your email address to contact you regarding any customer or technical support issues.

_Account Login_. The personal information you provide will allow you to log in to the Site and TRS Services.

We keep track of your interactions with us, including but not limited to your activity within the TRS Services, as further described below. We may use personal information that you provide to us to send messages to you in response to your request to perform an activity in connection with your use of any of the TRS Services.  We may also use your personal information to contact you when necessary.

_Generally._   In addition, we may use your personal information that we collect about you:  (1) to process your registration with the Site and/or any of the TRS Services, including verifying your information is active and valid; (2) to improve the Site and/or TRS Services or create new service offerings, to customize your experience on the Site and/or any of the TRS Services, or to serve you specific content that is most relevant to you; (3) to contact you with regard to your use of the Site and/or any of the TRS Services and, in our discretion, changes to the Site and/or any of the TRS Services  and/or any of the Site and/or TRS Services’ policies; (4) for internal business purposes; and (5) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your information or as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy.

_Use of Information for Recruitment Purposes_.  Where you have provided us with personal information as part of an online application for employment or internship, we may use that information in order to allow us to make an informed decision about whether to proceed with your application.  We may, as part of this recruitment process, collect information about your education, employment history and similar matters.  Where this personal information is considered to be sensitive, you expressly consent to our processing of this information for recruitment purposes by submitting it to us.

_De-Personalizing Your Information_

We may make your personal information non-personally identifiable by either combining it with information about other users (aggregating your personal information with information about other users), or by removing characteristics (such as your name or email address) that make the information personally identifiable.  This process is known as de-personalizing your information.  You grant us a royalty-free, worldwide, perpetual, irrevocable and fully transferable right and license to use your personal information in connection with the creation and development of analytical and statistical analysis tools relating to the use of the customer data we collect on the Site and TRS Services (the “ ** _Analytical Data_** ”).  We are expressly authorized to make any commercial use of the Analytical Data, including without limitation, sharing the Analytical Data with third parties.

_Cookies  and other Technical Information_

In addition to any personal information or other information that you choose to submit to us via the TRS Services, we and our third-party service providers may use a variety of technologies that automatically (or passively) store or collect certain information whenever you visit or interact with the Site and/or TRS Services (“ ** _Usage Information_** ”).  This Usage Information may be stored or accessed using a variety of technologies that may be downloaded to your personal computer, browser, laptop, tablet, mobile phone or other device (a “ ** _Device_** ”) whenever you visit or interact with the Site and/or TRS Services.  To the extent we associate Usage Information with your Personal Information we collect directly from you on the Site and/or TRS Services, we will treat it as personal information.

“Cookies” are small bits of electronic information that a website sends to a visitor’s browser and are stored on the visitor’s hard drive.  Like many websites, we employ cookies in certain areas of the Site to allow us to provide information to make your online experience more convenient and to enhance your experience with the Site.  For example, when you return to the Site after logging in, cookies provide information so that the Site will remember who you are on subsequent visits, speeding up or enhancing your experience of the Site by, for instance, tailoring content to you.  A user may configure his or her web browsers to accept or reject or delete the cookies, or notify the user when a cookie is being set.

We may collect other Usage Information from users of the Site and/or TRS Services, including their IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and geolocational information.

_Web Beacons_

We employ third party tracking utility software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective.  Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users.  In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence.  In short, clear gifs enable two websites to share information with one another.  We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personal information.

_Tracking Pixel_

A tracking “pixel” is a transparent graphic image (usually 1 pixel x 1 pixel) that is placed on a web page and allows for the collection of information regarding the use of the web page that contains the tracking pixel. TRS uses third party ad servers to support tracking pixels and cookies.

_Third Party Tools_

Our Site uses the following third party website tracking tools to help us learn about who visits our site and what pages are being viewed. Please click on the links below to learn more about these vendors and their privacy policies:

Google Analytics – <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

SumoMe – <https://help.sumome.com/customer/portal/articles/1963436-privacy-policy>

_Social Media Features_

Our Site interfaces with social media sites such as Facebook, Twitter, Google Plus and others.  If you choose to log in to your account on the Site through those social media sites, then TRS may access your information on those sites and import, use, and share your “friends” list or contacts from those sites.  If you choose to “like” or share personal information through those services, you should review the privacy policy of that service.  Those social media sites may collect your IP address or set cookies.  If you are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect and view your personally identifiable information.  In addition, we may provide third-party sites’ interfaces or links on the TRS Services to facilitate your sending a communication from the TRS Services.  For example, we may use third parties to facilitate emails, tweets or Facebook postings.  Further, when you use third-party sites or services, you are using their services and not our services and they, not we, are responsible for their practices.  You should review the applicable third-party privacy policies before using such third-party tools on the Site and/or TRS Services.

_Tracking Technologies Usage._  We may use tracking technologies for a variety of purposes, including:

_Strictly Necessary_.  We may use cookies or other tracking technologies that we consider are strictly necessary to allow you to use and access the Site and/or TRS Services, including cookies required to prevent fraudulent activity, improve security or allow you to make use of shopping‑cart functionality.

_Performance‑Related_.  We may use cookies or other tracking technologies that are useful in order to assess the performance of the Site and/or TRS Services, including as part of our analytic practices or otherwise to improve the content, products or services offered through the Site and/or TRS Services.

_Functionality‑Related._  We may use cookies or other tracking technologies that are required to offer you enhanced functionality when accessing the Site and/or TRS Services, including identifying you when you sign‑in to the Site and/or TRS Services or keeping track of our specified preferences, including in terms of the presentation of content on the Site and/or TRS Services.

_          Tracking Technologies Choices and Consent.  _We obtain your consent to our information storage or collection tracking technologies by providing you with transparent information in our Privacy Policy and providing you with the opportunity to make a choice to disable cookies as set forth above.  Please note that we are not required to obtain your consent to the information collection Tracking Technologies identified above that are strictly necessary.  If you are a resident of Europe, you may have the right to object to other use of information storage or collection technologies.

_Third Party Tracking and Do Not Track.   _There may be other tracking technologies now and later devised and used by us in connection with the TRS Services.  Third parties may use tracking technologies in connection with the TRS Services, which may include the collection of information about your online activities over time and across third party web sites or online services.  We may not control those tracking technologies and we are not responsible for them.  However, you consent to potentially encountering third party tracking technologies in connection with use of the TRS Services and accept that our statements under this Privacy Policy do not apply to the tracking technologies or practices of such third parties.

Various third parties are developing or have developed signals or other mechanisms for the expression of consumer choice regarding the collection of information about an individual consumer’s online activities over time and across third party web sites or online services (e.g., browser do not track signals).  Currently, we do not monitor or take any action with respect to these do not track signals or other mechanisms.

**_CHILDREN’S PRIVACY_**

We are a general audience service and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13, allow them to create accounts, sign up for newsletters, use the TRS Services, or browse the Site.  If you are a child under 13 years of age, you are not permitted to use the Service and should not send any information about yourself to us through the Service.  We take children’s privacy seriously and encourage parents to play an active role in their children’s online experience at all times.  We urge parents to instruct their children never to give out their real names, addresses, or phone numbers, without parental permission, when on-line.  If you have any concerns about your child’s personal information, please contact us at [privacy@turtlerockstudios.com](mailto:privacy@turtlerockstudios.com).

**_HOW WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL  INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES_**

We will share the personal information we collect from you under the following circumstances:

_–   Protection of rights._  We will share personal information if we have a good faith belief that (i) access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process, such as a court order or subpoena, or a request by law enforcement or governmental authorities, (ii) such action is necessary to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues associated with the Site or TRS Services, or (iii) such action is appropriate to protect the rights, property or safety of TRS, its employees, clients, or users of the Site.

_–   Asset transfers.  _If we become involved in a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or other transaction involving the sale of some or all of TRS’s assets or a line of business, user information, including personal information collected from you through your use of the Site and TRS Services, could be included in the transferred assets.  Should such an event occur, TRS will use reasonable means to notify you through a prominent notice on the Site.

_– Service Providers and Partners._  We may share your personal information with third party vendors or service providers that we engage for the purpose of fulfilling product orders, processing information on our and your behalf, operating or hosting the Site and/or TRS Services, or providing services related to the online components of our games. For example, we may partner with other companies to process payments for the Site. Additionally, we may partner with other companies to process consumer surveys, fulfill prizes, or to process, analyze, and/or store data, including, but not limited to, Analytical Data. We may also provide your personal information, such as your email address, to our publishing partner, 2K Games, and its affiliates, in connection with the online components of our games. For example, we may provide 2K Games your email address so that 2K Games may send you an invite to participate in the alpha or beta testing of our games or to access certain parts of our forums which are only available to game testing participants. While providing services for us, these companies may access your personal information. To the extent applicable, we require these entities to comply with this Privacy Policy and appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

– _Your California Privacy Rights_. **  **Under California law, California residents who have an established business relationship with TRS or one of its affiliates may choose to opt out of TRS’ disclosure of personal information about them to third parties for direct marketing purposes.  Our policy is not to disclose personal information collected online to a third party for direct marketing purposes if you elect to opt-out of such disclosure.  If you choose to opt-out at any time, email: [privacy@turtlerockstudios.com](mailto:privacy@turtlerockstudios.com) or write to Turtle Rock Studios, Inc., 25422 Trabuco Road #105-491, Lake Forest, CA 92630; Attn: Legal Department.

_Additional Information You Should Know About Third Parties_

This Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices of third party websites linked to the Site and/or technologies embedded in the Site and/or TRS Services.  Please be aware that we cannot control the activities of third parties to whom we provide data, and as such we cannot guarantee that they adhere to the same privacy and security procedures as TRS, but we take reasonable steps ensure that their policies are at least as restrictive as those set forth in this Privacy Policy.

Additionally, when you click on a third party logo or URL displayed on our Site which links you to a different website, our Privacy Policy no longer applies and you must read the privacy policy of the third party to see how your personal information will be handled on their website.  If you cannot find their privacy policy, then you should contact the respective webmasters of those websites to obtain information regarding their information collection, use and disclosure policies.  We are not responsible for their collection and use of your personal information.

**_WHAT  CHOICES DO YOU HAVE ABOUT THE COLLECTION AND USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?_**

When you provide us with personal information, you consent to our collecting, using, and sharing it in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  If we ask for your personal information for a secondary reason, we will either ask you directly for your expressed consent, or provide you with an opportunity to say no.

_Control of Your Information_

TRS allows you to control the way we use personally identifying information that we might obtain.  At the time you provide personal information, TRS may give you the option of declining any future offers or information about new products, promotions, or services.  In addition, many of the “mailings” TRS may send you, such as newsletters, have procedures within them to cancel the receipt of any future mailings.  Lastly, you may “opt-out” of certain third-party sharing by requesting the deletion of your personal information.

The Site and/or TRS Services may permit you to submit ideas, photographs, user profiles, writings, music, video, audio recordings, computer graphics, pictures, data, questions, comments, suggestions or other content, including personal information (collectively, “ ** _User Content_** ”), such as on blogs and message boards.  We or others may store, display, reproduce, publish, distribute or otherwise use User Content online or offline in any media or format (currently existing or hereafter developed) and may or may not attribute it to you.  Others may have access to this User Content and may have the ability to share it with third parties.  Please think carefully before deciding what information you share, including personal information, in connection with your User Content.  Please note that TRS does not control who will have access to the information that you choose to make public, and cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy or keep it secure.  We are not responsible for the privacy or security of any information that you make publicly available on the Site and/or TRS Services or what others do with information you share with them on the Site and/or TRS Services.  We are not responsible for the accuracy, use or misuse of any User Content that you disclose or receive from third parties through the TRS Services.

_Data Retention_

TRS retains the collected data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.  Thereafter, TRS deletes all aforementioned data in its possession within a reasonable timeframe.  TRS does not verify the correctness of personal data, but does allow you to update and correct information as set forth below.

Please note that some data may be retained if necessary to resolve disputes, enforce TRS’s terms of service, and comply with technical and legal requirements and constraints related to the security, integrity and operation of the Site or TRS Services.

_How to Opt-out, Correct or Delete Your Data_

Any individual who seeks access, or who seeks to opt-out of certain third party sharing, correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his or her query to the below email or physical address.  If, for any reason, you are concerned with the way we are using your personal information, or would like to request that we delete such personal information, please contact us at [delete-account@turtlerockstudios.com](mailto:delete-account@turtlerockstudios.com), or by mail at Turtle Rock Studios, Inc., ATTN: PRIVACY OPT-OUT, Turtle Rock Studios, Inc., 25422 Trabuco Road #105-491, Lake Forest, CA 92630.

We will make good faith efforts to make requested changes in our then active databases as soon as reasonably practicable (but we may retain prior information as business records). In some cases, we may not be able to delete your personal information, and will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**_Governing Law_**

This Privacy Policy is governed by, and construed under, the laws of the United States of America and the laws of the State of California, excluding its choice of law provisions.

_Mediation_

If you are a resident of a country outside the European Union, you agree that, in the event any dispute or claim arises out of or relating to this Privacy Policy, you and TRS will attempt in good faith to negotiate a written resolution of the matter directly between the parties.  You agree that if the matter remains unresolved for forty-five (45) days after notification (via certified mail or personal delivery) that a dispute exists, all parties shall join in mediation services in Orange County, California with a mutually agreed mediator in an attempt to resolve the dispute.  Should you file any arbitration claims, or any administrative or legal actions without first having attempted to resolve the matter by mediation, then you agree that you will not be entitled to recover attorneys’ fees, even if you would otherwise be entitled to them.

_Dispute Resolution for Residents of the European Union_

If you are a resident of the European Union, in the event that you have any dispute or claim arising out of or relating to this Privacy Policy, you may report your claim to the European Union Data Protection Authorities located in your jurisdiction.

**_European Commission’s Directive on Data Protection – Safe Harbor_**

The Site and TRS Services are operated in the United States.  If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect, including personal information, will be transferred to, and processed, stored and used in the United States.  The data protection laws in the United States may differ from those of the country in which you are located, and your personal information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United States according to laws of the United States.  By using the Site and TRS Services or providing us with any information, you consent to the transfer to, and processing, usage, sharing and storage of your information, including personal information, in the United States as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

Please note that TRS complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland.  TRS has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view TRS’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

If you are a resident of Europe, including Switzerland, you may have the right to ask us not to process certain of your personal data (or provide it to third parties to process) for marketing purposes.  You can exercise your right, if applicable, to prevent such processing at any time by contacting us in the following ways:  Postal Mail: Turtle Rock Studios, Inc., ATTN: EUROPEAN PRIVACY, Turtle Rock Studios, Inc., 25422 Trabuco Road #105-491, Lake Forest, CA 92630; By e-mail: [privacy@turtlerockstudios.com](mailto:privacy@turtlerockstudios.com).

**_WHAT SECURITY MEASURES DO WE TAKE TO SAFEGUARD YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?_**

The personal information that you provide to us is stored on servers that are located in secured facilities and protected by protocols and procedures designed to ensure the security of such information.  In addition, TRS employees and agents who have access to your personal information are trained in the maintenance and security of that information.   We take reasonable steps to ensure any third party agents handling personal information on our behalf provide at least the same level of protection as set forth in this Privacy Policy.  However, no server, computer or communications network or system, or data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  As a result, while we strive to protect user information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or through the Site or TRS Services and you acknowledge and agree that you provide such information and engage in such transmissions at your own risk.  Once we receive a transmission from you, we will endeavor to maintain its security on our systems.

**_Notification of Changes_**

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time and we will post all changes on the Site.  You understand and agree that you will be deemed to have accepted the updated Privacy Policy if you use the Site or TRS Services after the updated Privacy Policy is posted on the Site.  If at any point you do not agree to any portion of the Privacy Policy then in effect, you must immediately stop using the Site and TRS Services.  To the extent any provision of this Privacy Policy is found by a competent tribunal to be invalid or unenforceable, such provision shall be severed to the extent necessary for the remainder to be valid and enforceable.

**_Questions?   Contact Us_**

If you have any questions about our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at <https://www.turtlerockstudios.com/our-studio/contact-us/>

**__Terms of Use__**

Please read the [Terms of Use](https://www.turtlerockstudios.com/terms-of-use/) ** ** governing the use of the Site(s) and the TRS Features.  **_By using our Site and TRS Services_ , _you consent to our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service and our collection, use and sharing of your information and data, and other activities, as described above._**
